So we've talked about scoped.
What about CSS modules?
You might not have heard a lot about it,
but, and this is a feature that's not
talked about a lot about, but what you can do
is you can actually go ahead and tell your module,
or your CSS styles, to take on the module mode.
Now, what this will do, though, is a little bit tricky,
though, on the other hand.
So let me show you what's happening.
So right now, we'll notice that nothing's happening
to the button right now, because CSS modules
works really well in view, or I think, honestly,
I think in JavaScript scenarios, when there's
an actual class associated with it.
So just to switch this up to show that it's equivalent,
let me start by reverting this real quick.
So we'll use a class of button, rather than just
a generic button selector.
And we'll show that this, on the button count, the base
counter, let's make sure everything is equivalent.
So all the buttons here, one, two, three,
are going to get a class of button.
So there we go.
There's that red showing up, as we would expect.
And on the user card, we get a class of button.
All right.
So now everything is equal.
We're talking about CSS classes here now.
OK.
When we add the module here, what this is going to do
is this is going to allow us to do something that might seem
a little weird at first, but trust me on this one.
What we're going to do is we're going to vbind our class
attribute.
And so I'm going to do the shorthand now.
And rather than just bind it to button directly,
because right now it'll be like, what do you mean button?
There's no variable called button.
We're going to do dollar sign style.button.
That's what we're going to do.
And so what you'll notice here, actually, I
realized I only updated in one place.
We didn't update it in all three.
So one, two, three, just like that.
OK.
So you might at first think, oh, that looks kind of ugly.
I don't like the JavaScript.
But let me show you what's actually
happening underneath the hood.
If you take a look here, what you'll notice
is that the class has actually now
been recompiled to actually have a unique hash at the end.
And this is really powerful, because what you end up getting
is the ability to actually truly scope your styles
to basically that particular component.
Because the odds of this getting overridden by something else
randomly is very, very low.
And if you want it to be even more specific,
there are actually ways to configure your compiler
to actually basically spit out a specific pattern of how
you want the modules to be spit out.
So in this case, for example, you'll
notice it tells you that the class of button is being used.
So that way you can at least search for a class button.
And then after that, of course, this is a randomly generated
hash.
At the bare minimum, this is to me the minimum style of DX
that I think I recommend when it comes to CSS modules
across frameworks.
It's because I've noticed that some CSS modules will actually
just hash the entire class.
And you could argue, oh, that's super unique.
But I'd also argue that is super hard to debug.
In fact, that's almost near difficult and possible to debug
because you're like, now I have to figure out the HTML where
that happens to apply.
And so what I typically recommend
when it comes to CSS modules is to also go ahead
and prefix the component name to it.
Now, granted, if your component names are super long,
then there might end up being a performance issue.
But that way you know exactly which component file to drop
into and where the CSS class is.
But this is a really great way to protect your CSS
for components.
Now, once again, I know that not everyone is in love
with this style syntax.
So what I tell people is this.
Remember that when you're using stuff in Vue,
you can do stuff where it makes sense.
Just because you want to use CSS modules
doesn't mean you have to CSS modularize your entire code
base.
You can just do it in the places where it makes sense.
And that way you don't feel like you have to, one, do it
across the entire code base.
But two, you can be selective about the techniques
that you use because, as we saw earlier,
scoped works really well when it's written well.
But then otherwise, in times you need to be very protective,
go ahead and try out CSS modules on it.
And again, this is something that's just built right
into the library.
So the moment you want to use it, it's there for you.
We won't show you this at this point,
because this will be additional configuration.
But just know that for these blocks as well,
a lot of us also use preprocessors
when it comes to using our styles.
And so what you should know is that you can actually
add attributes on here, like Lang CSS, for example.
And you'll need to actually configure your builder
to actually make sure it has the sass loader.
But once you do that, you can write your sass files in here,
just like you normally would, use all your sass syntax
as you would expect.
Question?
Is there a way to avoid the class bind style button?
Is there a way to use sass and bind to the parent element
in the component, and then sass?
Yeah, that's a great question.
So the question is around trying to,
instead of using the style to use sass to check out
what the class is of the parent, and use that to generate
the CSS, to wrap, and that's everything,
I've never actually done that particular approach.
I would imagine that if you were to approach that,
it might be kind of hard to do.
So I don't have a, I'll say that it sounds possible,
but it might be tricky to do.